Guide to the David Leavitt Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- May 2006 Acquisition, 1981-2005; 3; 21.96; (24 boxes)
  - Writings and related papers
    - "The Marble Quilt" author's file set, 2 (Box 29)
    - "Crossing St. Gottad" (Box 29)
    - "The List" (Box 29)
    - "Black Box" (Box 29)
    - "Heaped Earth", "Route 80", "We Meet at Last" (Box 29)
    - "The Scruff of the Neck" (Box 29)
    - "The Infection Scene" (Box 29)
    - House Beautiful (Box 29)
    - Forster's Selected Stories (Box 29)
    - "The Marble Quilt", 2 (Box 29)
    - Writers in New York (Box 29)
    - Speonk (Box 29)
    - Martin Bauman, 2 (Box 29)
    - Asperger's (Box 29)
    - [misc. papers] (Box 29)
    - "Florence" box 1 of 2, 9 (Box 30)
    - "Florence" box 2 of 2, 7 (Box 30)
    - Misc. Publicity, etc. (Box 30)
    - "The Marble Quilt" cover design (Box 30)
    - "Food of Love", 2 (Box 30)
    - "Food of Love", 4 (Box 31)
    - "In Maremma", 3 (Box 31)
    - Martin Bauman (Box 31)
    - The Marble Quilt, 9 (Box 31)
    - Misc. Magazine Articles, 5 (Box 31)
    - Jonah Boyd, 4 (Box 31)
    - Jonah Boyd, 15 (Box 32)
    - Jonah Boyd, 13 (Box 33)
    - The "M" Word (Box 34)
    - Poster: Barcelona and Modernity (Box 34)
    - Saveur etc. New York Review of Books, 2004 Fall (Box 34)
    - Saveur etc. New York Review of Books Classics, 2004 (Box 34)
    - Saveur etc. NY Times 7/11/1983, 1983 July 11 (Box 34)
    - Saveur etc. Saveur Apr. 2005, 2005 April (Box 34)
    - Saveur etc. (Box 34)
    - Turing notes, correspondence, 2 (Box 34)
    - Turing manuscript and drafts, 13 (Box 34)
    - Turing drafts with Jesse Cohens' edited version, 15 (Box 35)
    - Jonah Boyd proofs, 2 (Box 35)
    - Jonah Boyd reviews and publicity, 5 (Box 36)
      Related Materials
      There is an audiocassette related to this material that can be found in Box 59.
    - Miscellaneous, 2 (Box 36)
      Computer disks stored in Box 45.
    - [unidentified], 5 (Box 36)
    - Author's Guild (Box 36)
    - Houghton Mifflin Catalog (Box 36)
    - ["In Maremma" related papers], 3 (Box 36)
    - Martin Bauman (Box 36)
    - Calendar 1989 (Box 37)
    - "Maurice" introduction, 4 (Box 37)
    - [photograph] (Box 37)
    - ["Collected Stories" jacket] (Box 37)
    - Double Take (Box 37)
    - Collected Stories, 4 (Box 37)
    - "The New Penguin Book of Gay Short Stories", 5 (Box 37)
    - [unidentified typescript], 4 (Box 37)
    - [unidentified typescript], 2 (Box 38)
    - "The Body of Jonah Boyd", 3 (Box 38)
    - "The Body of Jonah Boyd" advanced reading copy, 2 (Box 38)
    - "The Body of Jonah Boyd" copy-edited manuscript, 3 (Box 38)
    - "The Body of Jonah Boyd", 7 (Box 38)
    - "The Body of Jonah Boyd" proofs, 3 (Box 38)
    - "The Body of Jonah Boyd", 6 (Box 39)
    - "Gourmet" articles on Florence (Box 39)
    - Panel with Gore Vidal (Box 39)
    - Miami Book Fair (Box 39)
    - Teaching, Hopwood Prize, etc. (Box 39)
    - Article for Gainesville Magazine (Box 39)
    - "Introduction to Apartment in Athens (Box 39)
    - Reviews, publicity, etc. (Box 39)
    - Introduction to "New Penguin Book of Gay Short Stories (Box 39)
    - Collected Stories (Box 39)
    - "Food and Wine" article (Box 39)
    - "Yale Daily News" (Box 39)
    - "Metropolitan Home" article (Box 39)
    - [Clippings] (Box 39)
    - [Unidentified dissertation] (Box 39)
    - [Miscellaneous correspondence] (Box 39)
    - Fan mail (Box 39)
    - "Indiana" (Box 39)
    - "Gay Short Stories" "The Tender Peel," [typescript] (Box 39)
    - "The Man Who Knew Too Much", 4 (Box 40)
    - "Jonah Boyd" (Box 40)
    - "Collected Stories" (Box 40)
    - Festival letters (Box 40)
    - Miscellaneous printed material, 9 (Box 41)
  - Audiovisual Material
    Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Videocassettes
      - "Telegioruale Raitre", undated; YCALMSS724_0001; 1; 00:02:27 (Box 42, Item barcode 39002102339265)
      - "Great Performance: The Lost Language of Cranes", 1992; YCALMSS724_0002; 1; 00:24:20 (Box 42, Item barcode 39002102339273)
        CBS Sunday Morning 1992 June 21; Entertainment Tonight 1992, June 25; Charlie Rose 1992 June 25
      - Unidentified1, undated; YCALMSS724_0003; 1; 00:02:44 (Box 42, Item barcode 39002102339281)
        A handwritten note in Spanish to David is included with the tape.
      - "Food of Love" [VHS] (Box 42)
        This is a commercial videocassette. It has not been digitized.
      - "Hedwig and the Angry Inch" [VHS] (Box 42)
    - Audiocassettes
      - Paul Rutman / [Barenbeim]: Wagner, undated; 1 (Box 42, Item barcode 39002099366248)
      - "Seeing the Lite," chain novel, chapter 1, 1987 January 18; 1 (Box 42, Item barcode 39002099366149)
      - "Seeing the Lite", chain novel, chapters 2-8, 1987; 1 (Box 42, Item barcode 39002099366156)
      - "Seeing the Lite", chain novel, chapters 9-14, undated; 1; Deterioration of the binders in this tape (sticky-shed syndrome) has made the cassette unusable. This tape has not been digitized. (Box 42, Item barcode 39002099366164)
      - "Seeing the Lite", chain novel, chapters 14-20, undated; 1; Deterioration of the binders in this tape (sticky-shed syndrome) has made the cassette unusable. This tape has not been digitized. (Box 42, Item barcode 39002099366172)
      - NPR's "Fresh Air," David Leavitt, undated; 1 (Box 42, Item barcode 39002099366230)
      - NPR's "All Things Considered," interview with Leavitt and Mark Mitchell, undated; 1 (Box 42, Item barcode 39002099366222)
      - Untitled, undated; 1 (Box 42, Item barcode 39002099366206)
      - WNYC, 2004; 1 (Box 59, Item barcode 39002099366131)
        This audiocassette is related to a folder of material that can be found in "Box 36.
      - "Seeing the Lite", chain novel, chapters 21-25, undated; 1 (Box 42, Item barcode 39002099366180)
      - WESUN, David Leavitt, chain novel, 1987 January 18; 1 (Box 42, Item barcode 39002099366198)
        Weekend Edition radio show
      - Untitled, undated; 1 (Box 42, Item barcode 39002099366214)
        NPR "All Things Considered" interview with Leavitt and Mark Mitchell.
    - Compact Discs
      - Julia P. Hersheimer, Brinkman Records, 1996 (Box 42)
      - Food of Love, presskit, CD, undated (Box 42)
  - Other Papers
    - Poster (Box 43)
    - Portrait of Leavitt (Box 44 (Roll))
    - Computer disks, 4 (Box 45)
      2006-ycal-0518-k-0001: "Backup/hd"
      2006-ycal-0518-k-0001: "Nuvelz"
      2006-ycal-0518-k-0001: "Gloria Conso Stories"
      2006-ycal-0518-k-0001: "Old fiction backups"
    - Portrait, 1987 (Box 60 (Oversize))
- December 2014 Acquisition, 1978-2010; 4; 9; (14 boxes)
  Purchased from James S. Jaffe on the Sinclair Lewis Fund, 2014.
  This acquisition consists of writings, including proofs and other papers relating to The Indian Clerk, correspondence, audiovisual materials, artwork, and printed materials.
  - The Indian Clerk, circa 2004-2010 (Box 47)
    Includes manuscripts, correspondence, and printed material.
  - Printed materials, ephemera and notes, 1987-2010 (Box 48)
  - Printed materials and ephemera, circa 2003-2008 (Box 49)
  - Printed periodicals, circa 2003-2010 (Box 50)
  - Printed periodicals, circa 2003-2010 (Box 51)
  - The Indian Clerk proofs, circa 2007 (Box 52)
  - The Indian Clerk, circa 2007 (Box 53)
  - The Indian Clerk, circa 2007 (Box 54)
  - The Indian Clerk, circa 2007 (Box 55)
  - The Indian Clerk, circa 2007 (Box 56)
  - Correspondence, circa 2005-2009 (Box 57)
  - Electronic media (Box 58)
    Restricted Fragile Material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Audiovisual materials (Box 59)
  - Painted portrait, possibly of David Leavitt, 1978 (Box 60 (Oversize))
- May 2016 Acquisition, 1935-2015; 5; 9.25; (14 boxes)
  Box 73 (electronic media): Restricted Fragile Material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Purchased from David Leavitt on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2016.
  Organized into four series: I. Writings and research, undated-2006. II. Personal papers and notesbooks, 1969-2015. III. Books, printed material, and ephemera, 1935-2015. IV. Electronic Media, undated-2014.
  Contains writings, personal papers, printed material, and electronic media relating to the life and work of David Leavitt.
  - Writings and research, undated, 2006; 1.92; (3 boxes)
    - Laidlaw drafts, undated; (6 folders) (Box 61)
    - Laidlaw drafts, undated; (4 folders) (Box 62)
    - Short essays and stories, circa 2006, undated; (2 folders) (Box 62)
    - Two Hotel Francforts research, undated; (6 folders) (Box 63)
    - Rustumjee, undated (Box 63)
  - Personal papers and notebooks, 1969-2015; 3.42; (4 boxes)
    - University of Florida teaching papers, 2000-2014; (2 folders) (Box 63)
    - University of Florida student evaluations, 2000-2010; (3 folders) (Box 63)
    - DVD case and photo negatives, undated (Box 63)
    - Passports, 1969-2016 (Box 63)
    - Postcards and correspondence, ca. 1993-2015 (Box 63)
    - Photographs, undated; (2 folders) (Box 64)
    - Correspondence, 1997-2014 (Box 64)
    - Clippings, notes, and documents, 1990-2013; (2 folders) (Box 64)
    - Medal and badge, undated, 2015 (Box 64)
    - Notebooks, undated; (8 folders) (Box 65)
    - University of Florida "Teacher of the Year" award, 2015 (Box 72)
    - Clippings, 1986-2013; 11 folders (Box 75)
    - Drawings, undated; 5 folders (Box 75)
    - Notes and documents, circa 1992-2015; 17 folders (Box 75)
    - Articles and publications, circa 1974-2015; 6 folders (Box 75)
  - Books, printed materials, and ephemera, 1935-2015; 4.33; (6 boxes)
    - Books, 1935-1999; (3 folders) (Box 66)
    - Books, 1984-2014; (4 folders) (Box 67)
    - Printed material and ephemera, undated, 2008; (3 folders) (Box 68)
    - Printed material, 1999-2014; (2 folders) (Box 69)
    - Books and printed material, 1998-2012; (2 folders) (Box 70)
    - Book and printed material, 1972-2015; (2 folders) (Box 71)
  - Electronic media, undated, 2011-2014; 0.25; (1 box)
    - "The Man Who Knew Too Much" audiobook, 2014; 8 (Box 73)
    - "Britain's Greatest Codebreaker" DVDs, undated (Box 73)
    - Electronic media, undated, 2011; 1; 2 (Box 73)